PETE RICHARDS

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

📞 937.620.7592 | 前 Denver, CO or Remote | 💟 pcrichards57@gmail.com |

in linkedin.com/in/peterrichards57 | 📅 github.com/PRich57

Summary

Ambitious Full-Stack Developer with a solid foundation in computer science and programming, combined with a passion for learning new skills, collaborating with team members, and developing optimized, user-friendly web applications.

Skills & **Technologies**

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, SQL, Python, JQuery, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDb, Mongoose, MySQL, GraphQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Computer Science Fundamentals, Problem Solving & Algorithmic Thinking, Team Collaboration & Agile Development, Project Management, Documentation Research, Data Analytics

Experience

SYMMETRY FINANCIAL GROUP

2021 - 2023

Life Insurance Agent

Denver, CO

Facilitate in-depth needs-analysis to handcraft insurance plans based on clients' preferences and financial status

2017 - 2020 Dayton, OH -Denver, CO

Hosted monthly shadow sessions for groups of new hires, imparting critical skills such as overcoming objections, ethical sales procedures, and consistent sales processes

ENTERPRISE RENT-A-CAR

Assistant Branch Manager

- Successfully managed a team of 30+ direct reports, demonstrating exceptional leadership skills, and oversaw all facets of branch operations while adhering to industry best practices
- Implemented strategic fleet management tactics that led to the doubling of the fleet size, propelling the branch to become the most profitable in Ohio, Indiana, and Kentucky
- Achieved an unparalleled customer service rating of 98 Enterprise Service Quality index, the highest in the history of the Midwest Group, for a flagship branch, while concurrently mentoring over fifteen employees to attain management-level promotions within a single year
- Attained the prestigious position of the top-ranked Assistant Manager in the Midwest Group by spearheading innovative marketing strategies tailored to the strengths of branch employees, resulting in enhanced relationships with corporate accounts and substantial business growth

Trainee, Management Assistant

- Spearheaded weekly branch meetings to proactively identify areas of success, meticulously analyze branch expenditures, and devise cost-saving strategies
- Scrutinized individual sales performance metrics, strategically capitalizing on revenue-enhancing opportunities, resulting in optimized profitability

2016 - 2017 Dayton, OH

Education

OHIO UNIVERSITY

2011 - 2016

Athens, OH | BS in Integrated Media & Minor in Business Administration

UNIVERSITY OF DENVER

Aug - Nov 2023

Denver, CO | Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

HARVARD UNIVERSITY

May - Nov 2023

Remote (edX) | CS50